{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of the following commands sets the secret password to Cisco?", "opta": "enable secret password Cisco", "optb": "enable secret cisco", "optc": "enable secret Cisco", "optd": "enable password Cisco", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The enable secret password is case sensitive, so the second option is wrong. To set the enable secret <password>, use the enable secret <password> command from global configuration mode."}, {"question": "You type the following command into the router and receive the following output:\nRouter#show serial 0/0\n        ^\n% Invalid input detected at '^' marker.\nWhy was this error message displayed?", "opta": "You need to be in privileged mode.", "optb": "You cannot have a space between serial and 0/0.", "optc": "The router does not have a serial0/0 interface.", "optd": "Part of the command is missing.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "You can view the interface statistics from user mode, but the command is show interface serial 0/0."}, {"question": "Which of the following commands will display the current IP addressing and the layer 1 and 2 status of an interface?\n show version\n show protocols\n show interfaces\n show controllers\n show ip interface", "opta": "1, 2 and 4", "optb": "2, 3 and 5", "optc": "3 and 4 only", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The commands show protocols, show interfaces, and show ip interface will show you the layer 1 and 2 status and the IP addresses of your router's interfaces."}, {"question": "You type show running-config and get this output:\n[output cut]\nLine console 0\n    Exec-timeout 1 35\n    Password BIXPASSWD\n    Login\n[output cut]\n\nWhat do the two numbers following the exec-timeout command mean?", "opta": "If no command has been typed in 35 seconds, the console connection will be closed.", "optb": "If no router activity has been detected in 1 hour and 35 minutes, the console will be locked out.", "optc": "If no commands have been typed in 1 minute and 35 seconds, the console connection will be closed.", "optd": "If you're connected to the router by a Telnet connection, input must be detected within 1 minute and 35 seconds or the connection will be closed.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The exec-timeout command is set in minutes and seconds."}, {"question": "What layer of the OSI model would you assume the problem is in if you type show interface serial 1 and receive the following message?\n\"Serial1 is down, line protocol is down.\"", "opta": "Physical layer", "optb": "Data Link layer", "optc": "Network layer", "optd": "None. It is a router problem.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "If you see that a serial interface and the protocol are both down, then you have a Physical layer problem. If you see serial1 is up, line protocol is down, then you are not receiving (Data Link) keepalives from the remote end."}, {"question": "Which of the following commands displays the configurable parameters and statistics of all interfaces on a router?", "opta": "show running-config", "optb": "show startup-config", "optc": "show interfaces", "optd": "show versions", "ans": "C", "explanation": "With the show interfaces command, you can view the configurable parameters, get statistics for the interfaces on the router, verify if the interfaces are shut down, and see the IP address of each interface."}, {"question": "Which of the following commands will configure all the default VTY ports on a router?", "opta": "Router#line vty 0 4", "optb": "Router(config)#line vty 0 4", "optc": "Router(config-if)#line console 0", "optd": "Router(config)#line vty all", "ans": "B", "explanation": "From global configuration mode, use the line vty 0 4 command to set all five default VTY lines."}, {"question": "You need to find the broadcast address used on a LAN on your router. What command will you type into the router from user mode to find the broadcast address?", "opta": "show running-config", "optb": "show startup-config", "optc": "show interfaces", "optd": "show protocols", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The command show ip protocols will actually show you the broadcast address for each interface - too bad it isn't a possible answer. Your best answer is show interfaces, which will provide the IP address and mask for each interface."}, {"question": "Which command will delete the contents of NVRAM on a router?", "opta": "delete NVRAM", "optb": "delete startup-config", "optc": "erase NVRAM", "optd": "erase start", "ans": "D", "explanation": "The erase startup-config command erases the contents of NVRAM and will put you in setup mode if the router is restarted."}, {"question": "What keystroke will terminate setup mode?", "opta": "Ctrl+Z", "optb": "Ctrl+^", "optc": "Ctrl+C", "optd": "Ctrl+Shift+^", "ans": "C", "explanation": "You can exit setup mode at any time by using the keystroke Ctrl+C."}, {"question": "What command do you type to save the configuration stored in RAM to NVRAM?", "opta": "Router(config)#copy current to starting", "optb": "Router#copy starting to running", "optc": "Router(config)#copy running-config startup-config", "optd": "Router#copy run startup", "ans": "D", "explanation": "To copy the running-config to NVRAM so that it will be used if the router is restarted, use the copy running-config startup-config command (copy run start for short)."}, {"question": "You type Router#sh ru and receive an % ambiguous command error. Why did you receive this message?", "opta": "The command requires additional options or parameters.", "optb": "There is more than one show command that starts with the letters ru.", "optc": "There is no show command that starts with ru.", "optd": "The command is being executed from the wrong router mode.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The % ambiguous command error means that there is more then one possible command that starts with ru. Use a question mark to find the correct command."}, {"question": "If you wanted administrators to see a message when logging into the router, which command would you use?", "opta": "message banner motd", "optb": "banner message motd", "optc": "banner motd", "optd": "message motd", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The typical banner is a message of the day (MOTD) and is set by using the global configuration mode command banner motd."}, {"question": "How many simultaneous Telnet sessions does a Cisco router support by default?", "opta": "2", "optb": "3", "optc": "4", "optd": "5", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Cisco routers, if they do not have the Enterprise edition of the IOS, will default to 5 simultaneous Telnet sessions."}, {"question": "You set the console password, but when you display the configuration, the password doesn't show up; it looks like this:\n[output cut]\nLine console 0\n    Exec-timeout 1 44\n    Password 7098C0BQR\n    Login\n[output cut]\nWhat cause the password to be stored like this?", "opta": "encrypt password", "optb": "service password-encryption", "optc": "service-password-encryption", "optd": "exec-timeout 1 35", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The command service password-encryption, from global configuration mode, will encrypt the passwords."}, {"question": "Which command will show you whether a DTE or a DCE cable is plugged into serial 0?", "opta": "sh int s0", "optb": "sh int serial 0", "optc": "show controllers serial 0", "optd": "show serial 0 controllers", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The show controllers serial 0 command will show you whether either a DTE or DCE cable is connected to the interface. If it is a DCE connection, you need to add clocking with the clock rate command."}, {"question": "You want to totally reinitialize the router and replace the current running-config with the current startup-config. What command will you use?", "opta": "replace run start", "optb": "copy run start", "optc": "copy start run", "optd": "reload", "ans": "D", "explanation": "To completely replace the running-config with the startup-config, you must reload the router. Note : You may have picked option C, which isn't a bad answer. Remember, though, it doesn't replace the configuration, it appends it."}, {"question": "If you delete the contents of NVRAM and reboot the router, what mode will you be in?", "opta": "Privileged mode", "optb": "Global mode", "optc": "Setup mode", "optd": "NVRAM loaded mode", "ans": "C", "explanation": "If you delete the startup-config and reload the router, the router will automatically enter setup mode. You can also type setup from privileged mode at any time."}, {"question": "What is the problem with an interface if you type show interface serial 0 and receive the following message?\n\"Serial0 is administratively down, line protocol is down.\"", "opta": "The keepalives are different times.", "optb": "The administrator has the interface shut down.", "optc": "The administrator is pinging from the interface.", "optd": "No cable is attached.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "If an interface is shut down, the show interface command will show the interface as administratively shut down. (It is possible that no cable is attached, but you can't tell that from this message.)"}]]}